Guide to the Gerald Gunther Ppapers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2009-223
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 104, F. 22, Felix Frankfurter, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 104, F. 23, Felix Frankfurter, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 1, Felix Frankfurter, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 2, Felix Frankfurter, 1933-1935 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 3, Felix Frankfurter, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 4, Felix Frankfurter, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 7, Felix Frankfurter, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 8, Felix Frankfurter, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 5, Felix Frankfurter, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 6, Felix Frankfurter, 1938-1939 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 9, Felix Frankfurter, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 10, Felix Frankfurter, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 11, Felix Frankfurter, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 12, Felix Frankfurter, 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 13, Felix Frankfurter, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 14, Felix Frankfurter, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 15, Felix Frankfurter, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 16, Felix Frankfurter, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 17, Felix Frankfurter, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 18, Felix Frankfurter, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 19, Felix Frankfurter, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 20, Felix Frankfurter, 1953-1955 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 21, Felix Frankfurter, 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 22, Felix Frankfurter, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 23, Felix Frankfurter, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 24, Felix Frankfurter, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 25, Felix Frankfurter, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Photocopies of Transcriptions, Box 105, F. 26, Felix Frankfurter, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - GG-LH - L. Hand Search, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - GG - Inventory Overview, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Includes copy of Hand Papers manuscript collection finding aid (Harvard), 1968.
  - GG - Frankfurter Interview - Columbia, 1960-1962 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - LH - MHD, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - I-Inventory Overview - GG, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Hand Papers inventory.
  - 2-LH Papers Inventory - LHP, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - 3-General Correspondence (LH) I.GG A to Z, Undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - 4-General Correspondence (LH) I.GG Academy to Hammers, Undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - 5-General Correspondence I.GG Hammond to Northrup, Undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - 6-General Correspondence I.GG Nussbaum to Zabriskie, Undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - 8-General Correspondence I.GG Abruzzo to McBride, Undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - 9-General Correspondence I.GG McCann to Zlinkoff, Undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - 10-General Correspondence I.GG Aidinoffto Legal Aid Soc., Undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - 11-General Correspondence I.GG Lehmann to Zukor, Undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - 12-Personal Correspondence (II) Extended (A), Family (B), Undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - 13-Ali (III), Harvard (IV) Misc. Activities (V) - GG, Undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - 14-Writings, etc. (VI) Bio and Bibliog. (VII) - GG, Undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - 15-U.S. District Court Opinions 1-552 (VIII) - GG, Undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - 16-U.S. District Court Opinions 553-1153 (VIII) - GG, Undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - 17-U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals IX - GG, Undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - 18-Miscellany X, Addenda XI - GG, Undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Private Affairs (Hand), 1909-1924 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - District Ct. Work - Patents, Undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
    Includes GG notes on LH papers, box 47-65.
  - Frances Arnold Interview, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    Includes transcript of GG interview with Arnold, 1973.
  - C-LH - Vicario, Frances Holter, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    Includes notes on GG interview with Holter, 1982.
  - Cromwell-LH - Lloyd Garrison, 1973-1985 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    Includes transcript of GG interview with Garrison, 1973.
  - Cromwell-LH - R. Minton Sedgwick, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    Includes notes on GG interview with Sedgwick, 1972.
  - Harvard Law School Library Exhibits (Hand), 1972 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Julie Carlin Paper on Hand and the Fourth Amendment, Undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Loose Research Material, circa 1940s-1985 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - "An Analysis of Why Learned Hand Was Never Appointed to the Supreme Court", 1972 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    Student paper, Legal History Workshop, spring 1972.
  - General Correspondence, Recommendation Request, Ralph Zarefsky, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - General Correspondence, Ruth Bader Ginsburg, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Album of Judicial Opinions, 1918-1919 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Photocopied from a book (or books), case reporters?, and pasted into this album. Pagination out of sequence.
  - LH - Draft Book Outline, 1988-1992 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Includes information on the Prospectus, Rev. Outline, Binder Contents, Introduction, Chapter Headings, Foreword, Preface and Outline.
  - Introduction, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Prospectus - LH: The Man and Judge, 1985-1988 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - D. Ct. Work - Free Speech, 1909-1924 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - CCA - Constitutional, 1924-1939 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - D. Ct. Work - Constitutional, 1909-1924 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - C-LH Hand Research - Frank-Clark Debate on Legal Education, Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - LH - O.W. Holmes Papers, 1916-1974 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Loose GG-LH Research Materials, 1914-1973 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Includes correspondence and photocopies of manuscript materials.
  - GG Paper, 1917-1973 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - LH 13-1 through LH 13-10 Chapter Drafts, Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "Some Reflections on the Learned Hand-Felix Frankfurter Correspondence," Gunther, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - LH - Miscellaneous Publications, 1951-1978 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Includes Jurisprudence-Edmond Cahn- "The Doubter and the Bill of Rights" and "Authority and Responsibility"; Michael Kahn-"The Politics of the Appointment Process: An Analysis of Why Learned Hand was Never Appointed To the Supreme Court"; 1972 Middlebury College newsletter and Learned Hand Bibliography 1872-1961.
  - LH- MHD, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Box 114 - Billings P., Aunt Harriet, Lydia, and assorted Learneds and Huns, Undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - LH Papers - Carton Lists, 1970-1978 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - 2- LH Papers Inventory-GG, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - 19-Paige Boxes/Card Indexes-GG, Undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - LH Papers Inventory, 1969 Apr (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - GG-Bob Weisberg Correspondence, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - C.C. Burlingham - Misc., 1922-1956 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - GG-Notes on/Copies of LH Correspondence, 1918-1922 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - LH Papers - G.G. Notes Box 34, General Correspondence, 1909-1924 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Copies of LH-Felix Frankfurter Correspondence (1 of 2), 1911-1927 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Copies of LH-Felix Frankfurter Correspondence (2 of 2), 1911-1927 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Student Paper: "Analysis of Index with Respect to Tax Cases, 1916-1938", A. Kaulins, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Loose GG-LH Research Materials, 1922-1970 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    Includes transcripts of speeches by LH, and clippings and articles by, and related to, LH.
  - Loose GG-LH Research Materials - Harvard Law School Library, 1931-1980 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    Includes correspondence with Harvard Law School Library curator, copies ofLH manuscript material, and C.C. Burlingham exhibit catalog.
  - Loose GG-LH Research Materials, 1954-1969 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    Includes photocopies of correspondence related to LH sent by Charles Wyzanski of the USDC.
  - Student Paper: "Good Moral Character and Moral Turpitude in Naturalization and Deportation Cases from 1939-1952: The Scope of a Judge's Power", L. Wheeler, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Loose GG-LH Research Materials - Publications (1 of 2), 1942-1958 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    Includes "Thomas Walter Swan" article by LH (Yale Law Journal, Vol 57 No 2),1947; "Radical Periodicals in the United States, 1890-1960" catalog; Harvard Law School Bulletin (Vol 9 No 5) cover story on LH, 1958; "Proceedings of the Bar of the Supreme Court of the United States and Meeting of the Court in Memory of Associate Justice Louis D. Brandeis, December 21,1942"; clipping from St. Louis Dispatch, July 15,1951 with an interview of LH; ABA Journal Vol 29, 1943, containing Hand article on Brandeis.
  - Loose GG-LH Research Materials - Publications (2 of 2), 1941-1952 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    Includes Harvard Alumni Bulletin, 1952 issue with cover story on LH; Yale Alumni Magazine, Vol 9 No 20,1941, containing speech by LH; ABA Journal Vol 33 No 9, 1947, with cover story on LH.
  - Psycho-History, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Student Paper - "What Courts Do in Fact: The Evolution of Jerome Frank's Jurisprudence", P. Barnett, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Mounted Photo of Bust of LH, Undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Student Paper - "Copyright Law: Statutory Interpretation Second Circuit Decisions 1939-1952", C. Curtis, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Loose GG-LH Research Materials, 1950-1989 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Includes articles, copies of manuscript Hand correspondence, published Frankfurter Papers finding aid, Stanford Law School Library exhibit catalogs.
  - Student Paper - "A Study of Freedom of Speech by Zechariah Chafee, Jr.", H. Fromm, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Student Paper - "The Recall of Judicial Decisions as an Issue in the 1912 Presidential Election", B. Naon, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - LH clippings from Harvard Archives, circa 1946-1951 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Includes articles from the New York Times, Readers Digest, and Life..
  - L. Hand Decisions (Unfair Competition Through 1944), Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Current LH - Miscellaneous, 1973 Jun 19 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Proceedings in Honor of Mr. Justice Frankfurter and Distinguished Alumni, At the Meeting of the Council Harvard Law School Association in Cambridge, 1960 Apr 30 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Occasional Pamphlet No. 3
  - Some reflections on the Learned Hand - Felix Frankfurter Correspondence, Gerald Gunther, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    The William Winslow Crosskey Lecture in Legal History, The University of Chicago Law School, November 18,1976.
  - Journal of Supreme Court History, Vol. 1, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - LH - New York Times Clippings, 1913-1924 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Basic Appendix Documents (1-16), 1916-1974 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - LH Correspondence Box List, Undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Cromwell- LH - Zechariah Chafee, Jr., 1921-1973 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - GG-Chadbourn Correspondence, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - C-LH - Stanford Essay, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Hand, Judge Learned - Articles Concerning (1 of 2), 1918-1973 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Hand, Judge Learned - Articles Concerning (2 of 2), 1918-1973 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Learned Hand - Notes, 1953-1954 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    Includes GG notes taken while clerk for LH.
  - Photocopies from Manuscripts Division, Harvard Law School Library, 1893-1977 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Memos on LH [illegible] periodicals (Xerox of items discarded), 1943-1988 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Chapter X, See 2b Memo (Clark, Frank, Patterson), 1990 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Hand Letters to Frank, from Yale, for 71-15 to 71-20 file, 1990 January (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - LH - C.E. Clark correspondence (Yale), 1939-1957 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - GG - Growing Up in Nazi Germany, 1989 May 4 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    Includes partial transcript, and supplemental memo, concerning Gunther's perspective on growing up in, and returning to, Nazi Germany, 1989.
  - GG and Lippmann interview, 1969 Jan 22; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 11)
    [accompanied box 4, folder 2]
  - GG interview with Mary Hand Darrell, 1970 Jul 24; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
    [accompanied box 6, folder 6]
  - GG interview with Constance Hand Morris, 1973 Aug 3; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
    [accompanied box 6, folder 7]